# Security Software Engineer

## CONTACT

+1 (646) 979-0481



alan.cao@nyu.edu



https://codemuch.tech



ex0dus-0x

# **SUMMARY**

Second-year university student and security engineer with 2+ years of experience in industry and academia. I specialize in architecting and auditing secure systems and software, while also incorporating offensive security research to help protect the digital ecosystem for all.

## **SKILLS**

Security: SAST, DAST, Systems Security, Binary Analysis, Penetration Testing, Vulnerability Assessment, Reverse Engineering, Malware Analysis, Cryptography

Programming: C/C++, Rust, Python, SQL, x86 Assembly, Go, JavaScript, HTML/

Tools & Technologies: Unix Shell, Git, Vim, Docker, Vagrant, Clang/LLVM, CI/CD, AWS, Sentry, Binary Ninja

Other: Technical Writing, Chinese Mandarin

# **EDUCATION**

## **New York University**

B.S Computer Engineering, Class of 2023

**GPA**: 3.58

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **OSIRIS Lab @ NYU**

Jan. 2020 to Current

Undergraduate Researcher

- Conducting security research and bug-hunting efforts in compiler security, specifically in C/C++ obfuscation, WebAssembly and LLVM.
- Maintaining lab infrastructure through internal development pipeline to deliver core backend services for training and research.
- Led security training sessions on reverse engineering and cryptography to engage with aspiring security students.

#### **Trail of Bits**

Oct. 2018 to Jan. 2020

Security Engineer (Intern)

- Improved symbolic execution engine Manticore to help support cryptographic software assurance for open-sourced projects.
- Implemented a fuzzing interface API and an ensemble-based fuzzing engine into the <u>DeepState</u> framework to empower security unit testing.
- Engaged in security assessments for corporate vendors, using both industry and in-house security tools to help disclose security issues.
- Published multiple articles on internship research to company blog to share knowledge with security community.

## Secure Systems Lab @ NYU

Apr. 2018 to Sep. 2018

Security Researcher (Intern)

- Made key contributions with PhD students on building CrashSimulator, a mutation testing engine for syscall-based anomaly detection, helping detect lower-level runtime bugs before production.
- Created a QEMU-based testbed environment for CrashSimulator to perform bug-finding and replication for lower-level applications.

# VOLUNTEERING

#### **CSAW @ NYU**

Jan. 2020 to Current

• Co-lead and organizer for the collegiate CSAW CTF competition, involved in challenge writing and deployment, technical logistics, and infrastructural maintenance for 1,000+ teams in 90 countries.

#### **PROJECTS**

**Boa -** Web-based automated reverse engineering platform for black-box Python malware and executables (http://boa.codemuch.tech).

**Ghostpass** - Privacy-First Secrets Cryptosystem written in Go to prevent rubber-hose cryptanalysis (<a href="https://ghostpass.github.io">https://ghostpass.github.io</a>).

Brute - Crowd-sourced credential stuffing engine built for security professionals (https://github.com/ex0dus-0x/brute).

Binsec - The Swiss Army Knife for Binary (In)Security, a cross-platform utility used to detect binary security mitigations (https://github.com/ex0dus-0x/binsec).